Bryan Dimas

I am a web developer and entrepreneur.

I am the Co-Founder and former CTO of a small Houston-based startup called One Jump. I co-founded One Jump right after graduating from the impressively successful and intensive coding bootcamp The Iron Yard.

While working at One Jump, I developed about 75% of the entire website built with Ruby on Rails, but I also worked on a web crawler and a web scraper that we utilized to grow One Jump's database of Summer Opportunities. Both the web scraper and the web crawler were written in Python, and I effectively improved the web scraper's runtime by 845%.

After One Jump I secured an internship at OpenStax as a backend (Ruby on Rails developer) and it brought me up a whole new level!

Technical Skills

Likes:

ruby, ruby-on-rails, javascript, python, java

Experience

CTO & Co-Founder - One Jump

August 2015 - March 2016

ruby-on-rails-4, rails-postgresql, sidekiq, javascript, ruby, ruby-on-rails, python, web-scraping, twilio-api, heroku, omniauth, devise, rails-activerecord, github

I single-handedly expanded One Jump's Ruby on Rails application as the core of the business. I also worked on a web scraper which I improved the speed of by 845%, written in Python.

Startup Co-Founder & Web Developer - Raptorbird Robotics

2012 - 2014

php, html, css, c++

I created the startup's website with HTML, CSS, and PHP. We successfully launched a product and sold hundreds of them on KickStarter.

Software Development Intern - OpenStax

July 2016 - Current

ruby-on-rails-4, ruby-on-rails-3, ruby, postgresql

I worked as a backend (Ruby on Rails) developer on some of the most massive Ruby on Rails apps in history. OpenStax is a non-profit affiliated with Rice University and backed by great entities such The Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.

Education

Rails Engineering - The Iron Yard - Houston

2015 - 2015

ruby-on-rails-4, html, css, javascript, postgresql

The Iron Yard is a 12-weeks long intensive coding bootcamp that teaches to build fast, production-ready web applications.

Projects & Interests

One Jump - https://onejump.org/

ruby-on-rails-4, ruby, postgresql, javascript, sidekiq, python, web-scraping, web-crawler CTO

GitHub - OpenStax - Tutor - Server - https://github.com/openstax/tutor-server September 2014 - October 2016 ruby, ruby-on-rails-4, postgresql, rails-activerecord

Tutor-Server is the backend aspect of Tutor which provides Personalized Learning.

I worked on features to support the research team, I made several improvements to the admin console, and worked on other assignments such as gathering data for analysis of our user base.

GitHub - OpenStax - Accounts - https://github.com/openstax/accounts

July 2013 - September 2016

ruby, ruby-on-rails-3, postgresql, rails-activerecord

This Ruby on Rails app alone manages all the authentication and authorization for all OpenStax products!

I worked on security improvements and several other things.

Writing

BryanDimas - Co-Founder & CTO of One Jump - https://bryanelidimas.wordpress.com/

Lately, I have been blogging about Algorithms and Data Structures which I am studying under the tutelage of my Mentor whom graduated from MIT. He is a Senior Developer at OpenStax (https://www.openstaxcollege.org/about).